R Siraddeen

Github / in LinkedIn / ⊕ Portfolio Site / ≤ siraddeen15@gmail.com / ■ 6302029743

PROJECTS

Mini Social-media application

Link to Demo

Built an web application where users can able to post their images and other users can like & comment the post of the other users and in this app I have introduced a private chat rooms which are a real time Via socket.io along with web-sockets.

Blog / mini Medium application

Link to Demo

I developed a blogging website using a serverless backend via Cloudflare Workers and Hono. For database, I used Prisma ORM to generate automatic clients, which were used to create and manage the users and blog tables. For frontend. I used React+ TypeScript with Tailwind CSS for styling and React Router for routing functionality.

Real Time Chat application

Link to Demo

A real time chat application where the signup user can see the other users in the application and able to directly chat with them in the real time. This application use socket.io for this real-time communication

WORK EXPERIENCE

Internship at Codtech It Solution

Jul 2024 - Aug 2024

Successfully completed an internship in full-stack web development at Codtech IT Solutions. During this time, I worked on various real-time projects, which helped me to gaining practical knowledge and hands-on experience in web development.

Link to certificate

Hakirat Cohort 0-100 Nov 2023 – Jul 2024

Participated in the Hakirat Cohort, where I learned web development at an industrial level. The cohort provided in-depth training on Prisma, serverless deployment, and other essential backend technologies. This experience significantly enhanced my skills and understanding of web development.

Link to Certificate

EDUCATION

BTech at Quba College of Engineering Technology

Diploma at Siddharth Institute of Engineering Technology

SSC at ZPHS

Jun 2019 - Jul 2022 (Percentage: 73)

Jul 2016 - Jun 2019 (Percentage:81)

Jun 2011 - Jul 2016 (GPA: 8.7)

SUMMARY

As a MERN Stack Developer, I possess a strong understanding of both Front & Backend management along with strong database management from the backend. I use Express for local webpages and Hono for serverless deployments. I have built various web applications to gain practical experience across different areas of web development. I am committed to continuously enhancing my knowledge and skills in web development every day.

SKILLS

Front-End Development:

- Languages & Frameworks: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Tailwind CSS, React, Next.js Back-End Development:
- Frameworks & Libraries: Express, TypeScript, Hono, Cloudflare Workers, Next.js,Redux Database Management:
 - ORM & Tools: Prisma ORM
 - Database Systems: PostgreSQL, Avien (Online Database), Prisma Accelerate(pool connection)
 - **Techniques:** Pooled connections, schema design, query optimization, data migration, and client generation, have knowledge in containerization via docker